Anthony Reid

AnthonyReid99@gmail.com github.com/AnthonyReid99 339 532 9313

SUMMARY

Software developer with experience writing both backend and frontend code for a variety of frameworks, including Meteor, Flask, Android, iOS, and more. Knowledgeable on topics such as API design, mobile development, frontend UX code, and algorithms. Comfortable engaging in full stack development and quick to learn new frameworks and languages.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Co-founder of Nimblenotes, a study and exam preparation tool for students, winner of 2014 UMass Boston Business Launch Competition. Received over \$15,000 in cash, legal services, and other useful resources. Recently featured on the front page of Product Hunt.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages | Javascript (Coffee and Vanilla), Python, Java, C
Frameworks | Meteor, Android, iOS, Arduino, Flask, Jquery, MaterializeCSS, Bootstrap
Software | Trello, Unfuddle, Youtrack, Intellij, Pycharm, Webstorm
Version Control | Git, Github
Operating Systems | Linux

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts Boston Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Graduated May 2015 GPA 3.8

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Director at Nimblenotes

June 2014 - Present

- Planned and developed web application in Meteor.
- Managed deployment and maintenance of application.

Developer at HourlyNerd

Sept 2014 - Jan 2016

- Worked with web server stack including NodeJS, Angular, Vagrant, Flask, Bootstrap, and SQLAlchemy.
- Helped develop frontend and backend of Angular and Flask business applications.

App Developer at Tangolu LLC

Sept 2013 - March 2014

- Developed a productivity application for Android that was released to the Google Play Beta store.
- Maintained project under git version control system.
- Helped design RESTful web service API for interactions between client app and web server.

Freshman Success Community Leader at University of Massachusetts Boston

Sept 2013 - April 2014

- Served as a leader of the Freshman Success Community, a community of gifted freshman designed to provide a network of guidance and support.
- Provided general help and tutoring to students in the form of group lectures and individualized assistance.
- Designed and wrote an Android application to interface with an Arduino server as part of a remote-controlled car project undertaken by the students.

Tutor and Grader at University of Massachusetts Boston

Sept 2012 – April 2013

- Worked as a tutor for students taking introductory computer science courses in Java and Python.
- Provided individual programming help related to Python, Java and other elementary computer science topics.
- Graded homework assignments and exams for multiple introductory-level courses.